LAND OF GOLDEN-EYED MONSTERS
- Lis, isn't it hard to handle
all that luggage by yourself?
Lis, isn't it hard to handle
I'll be fine.
The less the rest of you have to carry,
the greater my chances of survival.
So please let me take this.
I'd like to respect Lis's wishes.
All right.
You're a part of our
mercenary band too, after all.
If you get tired, don't hesitate to say so.
Right!
I'm counting on you to watch
our surroundings, Piggymaru.
We're good on food and water.
Our greatest challenge is...
Stick to the plan.
Now come on out!
It's similar to the reptilian monsters
I fought in the Ruins of Disposal.
The difference is that seaweed-like head...
Is it a seaweed-headed lizard?
Paralyze!
Poison.
Good work.
Did you achieve what you wanted, Tooka?
Yeah, we've cleared the first step.
Sleep.
I wasn't sure my skill would work on
the creatures in the Land of Monsters,
but Poison, Paralyze, and Sleep
all seem to be effective.
They're inferior.
Hmm?
They look similar,
but compared to the monsters
I faced in the Ruins of Disposal,
these guys are far inferior in strength.
So it seems the monsters in the so-called
Land of Monsters aren't too tough.
If this is all they've got,
they're no match for me.
Sir Tooka, what are you doing?
I think I saw this guy
somewhere in this book.
Um, is this it?
Yeah, that's him.
Apparently this seaweed-esque bit
is an ingredient for a forbidden item.
Something like the voice-altering
stone in the Lord of the Flies' mask?
That's right.
If you're interested, you can take it.
Are you sure?
I know I don't have to worry with you.
Thank you.
Everyone's happy to get special treatment,
and that wasn't a lie.
Seras would see right through me
if I didn't mind my words carefully.
All right, time to begin our conquest
of the Land of Golden-Eyed Monsters.
LAND OF THE GOLDEN-EYED MONSTERS
Thanks for the save.
You're next, Lis.
Coming, Sir Tooka!
You can slip on the stones, so be careful.
I will.
Tooka, shouldn't I just carry her over?
She wants to do it herself.
So we should respect that, right?
Even so, what if she should slip?
I-I'll be all right.
I know I can't keep relying
on you for everything, Big Sis!
Th-Thank you, little Piggymaru.
So you had a safety measure
in place from the start?
Well, you know...
I want to do all I can to support Lis
when she puts her mind to something, too.
She was in a situation similar
to what I went through long ago.
Tooka, are you saying...?
Yeah, I'm really just doing this for myself.
Hmm...
Wh-What's the matter?
It's nothing.
Though you should be mindful when
people say something like that.
It tends to mean they were talking about
something they didn't want you to hear.
Big Sis, is that true...?
Um, I know I failed to make it across, but...
No. We certainly weren't talking about that.
You don't often hear about children
born between elves and humans,
much less children born
to high elf and human parents.
So we were discussing what
a child born to Tooka and Seras
would be like if that happened.
Miss Seras?!
Are you sure you don't want to dry them out?
Yes, I'm sorry about this.
I got distracted and let my guard down.
How embarrassing of me.
So even you get distracted sometimes, hmm?
I can't tell if this leopardman
is sharp or dense.
We can't have you catch a cold.
At least wear this.
Huh? Oh, no, I'm fine.
Go on.
Then... I hope you don't mind me borrowing it.
I wash it pretty regularly.
Oh, please, don't worry about that.
You don't mind 'cause it smells like me?
Precisely.
I see.
I meant that as a joke.
I meant that as a joke, but...
What's the matter?
We're turning back, Lis.
Huh?
They found us. Tooka!
Lis, over here.
Monsters you recognize?
Yeah.
Sorry, I can't beat these.
I see.
Are these what forced you and Lis
to flee the Land of Monsters?
Your orders, Tooka?
Stand back this time.
Understood.
I don't have time to prepare
my combo attack with Piggymaru.
I see. You guys are...
You're opponents not even the greatest
bloodsport warrior could defeat!
Welcome...
into my range!
Paralyze!
I won't give you a real fight.
You gleefully made your way here upon
spotting the prey you'd once let get away,
not realizing you were the ones
being hunted this time.
Berserk.
Sorry, but I'm finishing you off quick.
TOOKA MIMORI
- You have leveled up.
- Finally gained another level, did I?
Now then, Tooka...
Before the fight,
you sounded as if you knew of
these monsters from somewhere.
They're probably nazorts.
Just as I thought.
Tooka...
D-Don't tell me you plan
on eating that thing.
Don't get the wrong idea, Eve.
It's in Forbidden Arts: Complete Works,
which I borrowed.
As I recall, it's one of the ingredients
for enhancing slimes like Piggymaru.
- Isn't it?
- Yeah.
So that's what you're up to?
Hmm.
So Piggymaru will be the one ingesting
that creepy, spongy substance.
It's fine.
Once the enhancement solution is finished,
it won't look like this.
Probably.
Sir Tooka?
What?
Eve, can you sense anything?
I'm not sure.
There was definitely a monster,
but it was so brief.
Seras?
My spirits aren't responding either.
But something's there, no doubt.
And very close.
There's no malice or hostility.
Where is it?
What?
It's coming from me?
Sir Tooka, that's...
Yeah.
I guess it's about to hatch?
A-A horse?
Hey, Eve...
I feel like it got even bigger after hatching.
You noticed that too?
Is it a type of monster?
I know of several equine monsters, but this...
So not even you know it, huh?
Sir Tooka!
It's all right.
It has no hostility toward us.
A pony...
Hmm? What's this?
Pardon me.
This? It's an organ for absorbing magic.
It's a unique feature often found
in monsters and magical creatures.
I see...
Could everyone but Piggymaru get back?
And Eve, can I ask you to keep
an eye on our surroundings?
This little one might have increased in size
from absorbing the magic in the area.
And in that case...
Does that bother you?
TOOKA MIMORI
E-CLASS HERO
It's...
The horse is amazing!
I see.
So it possesses the ability
to transform by absorbing magic.
You consume roughly a thousand MP
for your transformation, huh?
This size seems perfect for hauling luggage.
Hold on, do you want me to...
You want me to pour even
more magic into you?
All right. Here I go.
Ninety-five hundred...
ninety-six... ninety-seven...
Ten thousand!
We may have just added an
interesting companion to our group.
Maybe it thinks of me as a parent.
It's part of our group?
Um, what are we going to name it?
Good question...
It's a fantastical horse.
With eight legs.
Slei...
The horse that Odin once rode,
the divine beast Sleipnir.
How about Slei?
It appears to approve.
We're happy to have you, Slei.
Huh?
S-Slei?!
I-I'd prefer you not do that there...
Seems it's taken a liking to you.
By the way, can you return
to your original form?
I see. That's a relief.
Don't just feel relieved! Please stop it!
I'm sorry. This is all because we're weak.
No, you're all doing your best.
Good, good. Everyone's leveling
up at a nice pace.
All because of you, Asagi.
My group is talented.
We coordinate to snuff out monsters,
and in the end, we split the
experience like good friends.
Thanks to that, even our
timid little pigeon is leveling up.
Th-Thank you.
What's got you so on edge, Takuto?
I don't like this.
Huh?
They keep throwing weaklings at us, giving us
nothing but experience to appease us.
Like lessons for little children.
They've grossly underestimated me.
I'll need to teach those top fighters
just who I am.
Dangerous ones are on the way.
This feels likely to be too much
for the heroes to handle right now.
Okay, so...
Could you heroes stand back a bit?
Saber Tigers, can you tighten up
the defense around the heroes?
Stand back?
Wh-What is that?
Ew, gross! That's creepy!
I'll handle the one in front.
These are strong, so I might not have
the leeway to save the kill for the heroes.
Then I'll deal with the second
one coming up behind it.
Will you join us, Abyss?
Sure.
A-Amazing!
You're telling me to stand back...
Abyss, some of the monsters
have changed course!
They're after the heroes behind us!
- Leave them to me.
- against monsters of that level?
...against monsters of that level?
Draconic Buster!
My unique skill is only level four right now.
Revise how you see me already.
FUTURE RULER
- Behold the power of Kirihara,
THE POWER OF KIRIHARA
- your future ruler!
That reminds me... Where are
Hijiri-san and Itsuki-san?
Looks like something's going on over there.
Might be time for us to head back.
These guys offed themselves the moment
we discovered them, anyway.
I suppose that means they were spies
who'd sworn their lives to their master.
Which country would do this, though?
Now that's a good question.
I think they were dispatched to do
something to those of us in 2-C...
by the Goddess Vicius.
At least, that's my read on them.
I've finished preparing dinner.
Okay.
Thanks to Slei, we're making much
better time than we expected.
Yes, it looks like it's not much
further to the Witch of Taboos.
What are you looking at?
I saw a strange light in the distance.
I thought it might be some
monsters killing each other off.
That's to the northeast.
The northeast?
Oh, I see.
The direction of Alion,
where that damn goddess lives.
Eve?
What is it, Seras?
I don't see Sir Tooka anywhere.
Or Piggymaru.
He's not the kind of man who'd leave us
in the middle of the Land of Monsters
without a word.
You should already know that well.
I do.
You're up?
Tooka, those monsters...
I sensed them nearby
while you were sleeping.
So I put them down.
That monster... Th-That's
a human-faced beast, isn't it?
Yeah.
Though, compared to what I'm used to,
it wasn't particularly troublesome.
Now I'm searching to see if it
has any ingredients I can use.
You took a human-faced beast all by yourself?
Am I still dreaming?
No, that's just how Sir Tooka is.
Indeed, because we have him,
we can see a ray of hope in this plan
to head into the nightmare that is
the heart of the Land of Monsters.
I'm confident you can make the
impossible possible, Sir Tooka,
but please...
don't shoulder too much all on your own.
Looks like it's impossible
to scale these cliffs, even with Slei.
Hmm, that means we'll have
to follow the road along them.
I found a path that continues through
the cliffs on the east side.
Let's hurry that way.
Sir Tooka, you should get some rest as well.
The wind's growing humid.
I want to get as far as we
can before the rains hit.
I don't sense any monsters yet.
This lack of monsters...
Do you think it's because of our
proximity to the Witch of Taboos?
Are you okay?
Yes.
Is the Land of Monsters scary?
I wouldn't say it hasn't been scary...
but I'm okay.
Don't go saying anything like,
"Dying here with Eve is better than
continuing to live in Monroy."
That isn't exactly wrong...
but I don't believe I'm going to die here.
Miss Seras told me that
as long as you live, Sir Tooka,
we should reach our destination safely.
She believes in me a little too much.
Still, thanks to her, I've held hope that
we'll be fine so long as we have you with us.
We have Slei, too.
Both Eve and Lis have complete faith in me.
It's fine.
I can see this through.
I have no intention of betraying that faith.
We were able to avoid most of the detours.
Once we're through here,
we'll be close to the witch.
We managed to make it this far somehow.
Indeed.
You've done well too, Lis.
Yeah.
I don't know how I can ever
thank you, Tooka and Seras.
Big Sis, you're forgetting Piggymaru and Slei.
You're right.
I owe you both my heartfelt gratitude too.
You've been a great help.
Well, we all needed your map too, Eve.
I told you, right?
I didn't help you out of goodwill alone.
So you're saying we're even.
You're so kind, Sir Tooka.
Yeah.
I don't care if our home is small,
as long as I can live a quiet life with
Lis in a peaceful land free from war.
The moment I thought my days
as a bloodsport warrior were over
and that dream was finally in reach,
it was snatched from me.
But now I have hope
for that dream once more.
I know I talked about us starting a farm
together once this is all over,
but maybe that future
isn't so far off anymore.
Yeah. That's true, Big Sis.
Eve.
What? Completely out of nowhere?
Eve, wait!
That's not a human-faced beast, but...
Wh-What's the matter, Tooka?
Is that monster still breathing?
No, it seems to be dead.
It's not moving at all.
Paralyze.
Yeah, it's definitely dead.
Eve made the right call.
It caught us off guard at such close range.
That was definitely our best
course of action, but...
What is the intense sense of unease
I felt the moment it showed up?
Everyone, get back!
Don't tell me...
Wh-What was that just now? And this...
A heinous nature like the
embodiment of a torture device,
malice blacker than the deepest inks,
and a sadism darker than coal tar...
Now I get it.
They're closing in.
Wh-What?
They're flooding here from all directions.
But there...
There are far too many of them!
TO THE LIMIT, AND BEYOND